Welcome to AI Fundamentals for enterprise workflows. We focus on how AI and low-code combine for faster, governed change.
Large language models excel at understanding text, but they are not databases. Keep truth in systems of record and fetch facts with retrieval.
Blend LLMs for understanding with predictive models for scoring, and decisioning to arbitrate actions.
Prefer grounding over fine-tuning. Fine-tune only for narrow, stable, high-volume tasks with approvals.
Common patterns: classify, extract, summarize, route, recommend, and draft. Use structured outputs like JSON or tables.
Risks include hallucination, prompt injection, leakage, and bias. Mitigate with redaction, allow and deny lists, filters, and human review.
Evaluate both quality and business impact: precision, recall, factuality, plus cycle time and SLA adherence. Maintain golden test sets and inline monitors.
In Pega, Process AI provides signals, Decisioning selects the next best action, and GenAI connectors draft or summarize with bounded outputs.
Next steps: pick one friction point, design a bounded LLM task with structured output, and log everything.
Q and A. One: When do we fine-tune instead of retrieve? Only when the task is narrow, data is stable, volume is high, and approvals exist. Two: How do we prevent leakage? Redact PII, constrain prompts, use approved endpoints, and log all interactions. Three: How do we measure success? Track accuracy and business KPIs, test offline, and monitor inline.